const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Caplan syndrome consists of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Asbestosis and tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Byssinosis and rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumoconiosis  and rheumatoid arthritis","bool":true},{"option":"Silicosis and tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Berriliosis","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following is used to determine the pH of the buffer solution?","answers":[{"option":"Strong acid","bool":false},{"option":"Weak and strong acid","bool":false},{"option":"Weak acid","bool":false},{"option":"Weak base","bool":false},{"option":"Acid and conjugate base","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"What is the term used for the type of hypoxia that includes the disruption of oxygen usage of the cell by the toxic substances, even when there is high oxygen saturation?","answers":[{"option":"Circulatory hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Anemic hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxic hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Stagnant hypoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Histotoxic hypoxia","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A doctor checking a chest X-ray notices a rib having the subclavian artery on it. Which of the following ribs has the groove for this artery?","answers":[{"option":"2","bool":false},{"option":"6","bool":false},{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"4","bool":false},{"option":"1","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Where is the apex of the lung located?","answers":[{"option":"Below root of neck","bool":false},{"option":"Above 1st rib","bool":true},{"option":"Below clavicle","bool":false},{"option":"Below C1","bool":false},{"option":"Above 2nd rib","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which movement is involved in the increase in vertical diameter of the thorax during inspiration?","answers":[{"option":"Bucket handle movement","bool":false},{"option":"Downward movement of diaphragm","bool":true},{"option":"Downward movement of ribs","bool":false},{"option":"Upward movement of diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Pump handle movement","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following does not characterize the bronchopulmonary segment?","answers":[{"option":"Has its own vein","bool":true},{"option":"Pyramidal in shape","bool":false},{"option":"Has its own artery","bool":false},{"option":"Independent functional unit","bool":false},{"option":"Segmental bronchus","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A 4-year-old boy presents to the emergency department with complaints of coughing and wheezing after swallowing 5 rupees coin. The pulmonologist used a bronchoscope to perform foreign body aspiration to remove the coin. What is the most expected place for trapping of the foreign body?","answers":[{"option":"Trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Right bronchus","bool":true},{"option":"Left bronchus","bool":false},{"option":"Lobule of lung","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchioles","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"What is the level of bifurcation of the trachea?","answers":[{"option":"T3","bool":false},{"option":"Sternal angle","bool":true},{"option":"T6","bool":false},{"option":"Gastroesophageal junction","bool":false},{"option":"T4","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Paralysis of the diaphragm is caused due to injury of?","answers":[{"option":"Supraclavicular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Phrenic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Esophageal plexus","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following is responsible for the impairment of oxygen delivery to the tissues?","answers":[{"option":"Carbon monoxide poisoning","bool":true},{"option":"Running a marathon at sea level","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Previous history of cyanide poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"Doing exercise early in the morning","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"What is the type of epithelium found in the vocal cords of the larynx?","answers":[{"option":"Stratified cuboidal","bool":false},{"option":"Simple squamous","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous non-keratinized","bool":true},{"option":"Stratified squamous keratinized","bool":false},{"option":"Columnar ciliated","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which one of the following is a term used to describe a lack of sufficient oxygen delivered to the tissues?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Anoxia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoxia","bool":true}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of these is not found in the plane of sternal angle?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary trunk bifurcation","bool":false},{"option":"Bifurcation of trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Brachiocephalic trunk","bool":true},{"option":"Arch of azygos vein","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic arch","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of these substances is used to synthesize prostaglandins?","answers":[{"option":"Arginine","bool":false},{"option":"Arachidonic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Nitric oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygen","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following cells of the lungs secrete surfactant?","answers":[{"option":"Endothelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Type 2 alveolar epithelial cells","bool":true},{"option":"Secretory cells","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous epithelial cells of trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1 alveolar epithelial cells","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following types of cancer involves the chromosome 3p deletions and mutations in TP53, Rb?","answers":[{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Basal cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following organisms is most likely to cause pneumonia in an immunocompromised patient?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella pneumophila","bool":true},{"option":"Haemophilus influenzae","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"On examination of histological slides of the lung, students got confused between different bronchioles. Which of the following is the identifying feature that distinguishes respiratory bronchioles from other bronchioles?","answers":[{"option":"The type of epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"The number of cells","bool":false},{"option":"The presence of glands","bool":false},{"option":"The interrupted wall of lumen","bool":true},{"option":"The diameter of lumen","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following enzymes catalyzes the formation of bicarbonate ions from water and carbon dioxide in the blood?","answers":[{"option":"Protein kinase","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholinesterase","bool":false},{"option":"Carbonic anhydrase","bool":true},{"option":"Alkaline phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Adenylate cyclase","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"The pulmonary alveoli are cup-shaped structures and are composed of many cells. Which of the following are the alveolar cells present in alveoli that are cuboidal in shape?","answers":[{"option":"Great alveolar cells","bool":true},{"option":"Squamous alveolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar sac","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1 alveolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar atria","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Gases such as oxygen and carbon dioxide cross the plasma membrane by which of the following methods?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary active transport","bool":false},{"option":"Facilitated diffusion","bool":false},{"option":"Passive diffusion through the lipid bilayer","bool":true},{"option":"Primary active transport","bool":false},{"option":"Specific gas transport proteins","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following features clearly distinguishes bronchioles from bronchi under the light microscope?","answers":[{"option":"The type of cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"The type of glands","bool":false},{"option":"The presence of cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"The presence of smooth muscle","bool":false},{"option":"The absence of glands","bool":true},{"option":"The type of epithelium","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"What is the most common route carbon dioxide takes to be transported to the cells?","answers":[{"option":"By dissolving in plasma","bool":false},{"option":"In the form of carbaminohemoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"In the form of bicarbonate ions","bool":true},{"option":"In the form of carboxy hemoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"By binding to plasma proteins","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"pH value can be determined by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"pH detector","bool":false},{"option":"pH balancer","bool":false},{"option":"pH electrode","bool":false},{"option":"pH spectrometer","bool":false},{"option":"pH meter","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following does not drain into the thoracic duct?","answers":[{"option":"Right intercostal nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Left intercostal nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Left lower limb","bool":false},{"option":"Right lower limb","bool":false},{"option":"Left bronchomediastinal trunk","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Pleural effusion is checked on X-ray at which of the following levels?","answers":[{"option":"Costophrenic angle","bool":true},{"option":"Base of the lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiophrenic angle","bool":false},{"option":"Sternal angle","bool":false},{"option":"Infrasternal angle","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following factors shifts the oxygen dissociation curve to the right?","answers":[{"option":"High pH","bool":false},{"option":"Strenuous exercise","bool":true},{"option":"Low temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Low concentration of 2,3 DPG","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal hemoglobin","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Cardiac output is increased during strenuous exercise. How is the increased blood flow accommodated by pulmonary circulation?","answers":[{"option":"With decrease in pulmonary arterial pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Without large increase in pulmonary arterial pressure","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"With increase in pulmonary arterial pressure","bool":false},{"option":"With large increase in systemic arterial pressure","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following statements is correct about zone 3 of pulmonary blood flow?","answers":[{"option":"Alveolar capillary pressure remains greater than alveolar air pressure","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"It is present in the apices of lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar air pressure remains greater than alveolar capillary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"It receives intermittent blood flow","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"What is the total compliance of lungs in milliliters?","answers":[{"option":"1000","bool":false},{"option":"200","bool":true},{"option":"600","bool":false},{"option":"800","bool":false},{"option":"400","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which equation shows that pH of a solution is equal to its pKa when the acid and base are in equal concentrations?","answers":[{"option":"Water dissociation equation","bool":false},{"option":"Hardy Weinberg equation","bool":false},{"option":"Henderson-Hasselbalch equation","bool":true},{"option":"Torricelli's theorem","bool":false},{"option":"pH log equation","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"What is the pressure difference between alveolar pressure and pleural pressure called?","answers":[{"option":"Interpleural pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Atmospheric pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Interpulmonary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Transpulmonary pressure","bool":true},{"option":"Intrapleural pressure","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following is a prime indication of a high-resolution computed tomography scan?","answers":[{"option":"Empyema","bool":false},{"option":"Lung cancer staging","bool":false},{"option":"Mediastinal abnormality","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural disease","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial lung disease","bool":true}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A young male presents to the outpatient department with complaints of cough and dyspnea. The physician advises a chest X-ray for further evaluation. Which of the following projections is most appropriate for him?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral view","bool":false},{"option":"Oblique view","bool":false},{"option":"Anteroposterior view","bool":false},{"option":"Apical view","bool":false},{"option":"Posteroanterior view","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A person admitted to the hospital is in a coma. Analysis of arterial blood gave the following values: PCO2 25mm Hg, HCO3- 5mmol/l, and pH 7.1. What is the underlying acid-base disorder?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Mixed disorder","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"The definition of obstructive pattern in pulmonary function tests is best defined by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"FVC that is less than 95% of predicted","bool":false},{"option":"Maximal mid expiratory flow is less than 75% of predicted","bool":false},{"option":"Total lung capacity that is more than 70 to 75% of predicted","bool":false},{"option":"Total lung capacity that is less than 70 to 75% of predicted","bool":false},{"option":"FEV1/FVC that is less than 70-75% of the predicted","bool":true}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A mother brings her 1-year-old child to the primary healthcare center with complaints of fever and cough and not being able to feed. On examination, the respiratory rate of the child is 55 breaths per minute. There is chest indrawing and wheeze present and the child is lethargic and sleepy. What is the child's classification according to the IMNCI guidelines?","answers":[{"option":"Very severe disease","bool":true},{"option":"Mild pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"No pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Cough and cold","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A mother visits a primary healthcare center with her 2-month-old infant. She wants advice on how to prevent acute respiratory tract infections in her baby. Apart from immunization, which of the following is the most applicable preventative measure the doctor can advise her?","answers":[{"option":"Better hygiene","bool":false},{"option":"Breastfeeding","bool":true},{"option":"Immediate care in case of fever","bool":false},{"option":"Better nutrition","bool":false},{"option":"Control of indoor pollution","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A 35-year-old factory worker comes to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, chills, and pain in the right side of his chest. He has worked in a factory for 8 years. His blood count shows raised white blood cells, normal hemoglobin, and raised ESR. What is the etiology of this condition?","answers":[{"option":"P. aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"S. aureus","bool":false},{"option":"K. pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"S. pneumoniae","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A 47-year-old lady with diabetes comes to the hospital with complaints of fever and chills. The fever is associated with vomiting and cough. She explains she had the flu a week ago. Her total white blood cell count is raised and her culture shows the growth of Factor V and X. What is the causative agent of her symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"H influenza","bool":true},{"option":"E. Coli","bool":false},{"option":"P. aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"S. pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"K. pneumoniae","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A 56-year-old male presents to the emergency room with severe shortness of breath, fever, and cough. The cough is productive with yellowish sputum and has been increasing for the past 2 days. He has been smoking for 25 years. He has been hospitalized twice for shortness of breath. He is taking a bronchodilator preparation twice a day. He denies chest pain or hemoptysis. His temperature is 100 F, pulse 94 beats/min, respiratory rate 25 breaths/minute, and blood pressure is 130/86 mmHg. Pulmonary function testing shows FEV1/FVC ratio to be <70% with no bronchodilator reversibility. FEV1 is <80%. A chest X-ray done 4 months ago shows a hyperinflated lung. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumothorax","bool":false},{"option":"Acute asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary edema","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A 3-year-old boy is brought to the emergency department with a history of swallowing a foreign body. Which of the following is the site of the respiratory passage where it is likely to get stuck?","answers":[{"option":"Right bronchus","bool":true},{"option":"Tertiary bronchiole","bool":false},{"option":"Left bronchus","bool":false},{"option":"Upper rings of trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolus","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following is the correct stage of maturation of lung development in which the respiratory bronchioles are formed?","answers":[{"option":"Terminal sac period","bool":false},{"option":"Period between 5-16 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudoglandular period","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar period","bool":false},{"option":"Canalicular period","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"What is the amount of air that remains in the lungs after the normal tidal expiration?","answers":[{"option":"Expiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Functional residual capacity","bool":true},{"option":"Vital capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":false},{"option":"Inspiratory residual volume","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"There is an overlap between chronic obstructive pulmonary diseases and their etiopathogenesis. Which of the following obstructive pulmonary disease involves the acinus?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchiolitis","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":true}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Clinical signs and symptoms of pulmonary embolism mimic myocardial infarction. Which of the following is the most correct method of diagnosing pulmonary embolism?","answers":[{"option":"Venography","bool":false},{"option":"ECG","bool":false},{"option":"Chest X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Radioisotope perfusion pulmonary scintigraphy","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary arteriography","bool":true}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A 75-year-old man is hospitalized for the past week with COVID pneumonia. He develops sudden-onset dyspnea and tachypnea. His lips appear blue and his oxygen saturation drops drastically. Chest X-ray shows bilateral diffuse infiltrates (\"white lung\"). What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Fat embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Acute bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Miliary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute respiratory distress syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Septicemia","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"An 11-year-old child is brought to the clinic with a history of dry cough at night and early in the morning. She complains of her chest feeling tight and a whistling sound when she breathes out. Which of the following is true regarding this patient's condition?","answers":[{"option":"Most likely due to upper airway hyper-responsiveness to stimuli","bool":true},{"option":"Airways will be dilated up to 4 times the normal size","bool":false},{"option":"There is irreversible airway obstruction","bool":false},{"option":"Cough can be treated with cough supressants","bool":false},{"option":"Cough is due to chronic necrotizing infection of the bronchial walls","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A 30-year-old man suffers a head injury after a car accident. After a few days, he suddenly develops severe hypoxia, dyspnea, and goes into respiratory failure.  What is a lung biopsy likely to show in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Acute inflammatory cells in the alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth muscle hyperplasia and excess mucous","bool":false},{"option":"Scarring and airway dilatation","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelioid cells and Langhans giant cells","bool":false},{"option":"Hyaline membranes lining the alveoli","bool":true}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A 30-year-old woman who has a history of rhinitis and nasal polyps presents to the clinic with complaints of repeated asthmatic attacks and urticaria. On further inquiry, she reports taking aspirin for her lower back pain. What is the most likely cause of her asthmatic attacks?","answers":[{"option":"Aspirin causes increased leukotriene production which causes bronchospam","bool":true},{"option":"Polyps in the nose predispose her to polypi in the lungs as well","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin damages her distal airways causing them to dilate","bool":false},{"option":"She most likely has a positive family history for asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal polyps and rhinitis predispose her to necrotizing bronchial infections","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following ribs is characterized as an atypical but true rib?","answers":[{"option":"12","bool":false},{"option":"5","bool":false},{"option":"7","bool":false},{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"1","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"An injury to the phrenic nerve denervates which part of the parietal pleura?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral diaphragmatic","bool":false},{"option":"Costal","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical","bool":false},{"option":"Mediastinal","bool":true},{"option":"Apical","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following is present in expired air?","answers":[{"option":"Residual volume","bool":false},{"option":"Only carbon dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Dead space air","bool":false},{"option":"Dead space and alveolar space air","bool":true},{"option":"Alveolar space air","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Through which of the following anemia leads to hypoxia?","answers":[{"option":"Inadequate oxygen supply","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory decompensation","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperventilation","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoventilation","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased plasma protein","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following cells are not present in the mucosal lining of the nasopharynx?","answers":[{"option":"Clara cells","bool":true},{"option":"Diffuse neuroendocrine cells (DNES)","bool":false},{"option":"Ciliated columnar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Serous cells","bool":false},{"option":"Goblet cells","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"The pump handle movement of the rib cage involves which of the following ribs?","answers":[{"option":"1 to 7","bool":false},{"option":"7 to 10","bool":false},{"option":"2 to 6","bool":true},{"option":"2 to 10","bool":false},{"option":"7 to 12","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following is among the factors that obstruct effective communication?","answers":[{"option":"Reasonable eye-contact","bool":false},{"option":"Selective listening","bool":true},{"option":"Selective reflection","bool":false},{"option":"Active listening","bool":false},{"option":"Paraphrasing","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following is most likely to occur in the Haldane effect?","answers":[{"option":"Oxygen replaces carbon dioxide in blood","bool":true},{"option":"Oxygen replaces water in blood","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygen replaces chloride in blood","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygen replaces potassium in blood","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygen replaces hydrogen in blood","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following best explains the vertical model in the doctor-patient relationship?","answers":[{"option":"Patient makes all the decisions on their own","bool":false},{"option":"Patient plays a mutual role in deciding the treatment plan","bool":false},{"option":"Doctor helps patient find their preferences","bool":false},{"option":"Doctor only provides facts to the patient","bool":false},{"option":"Doctor taking entire control which is not apparent virtually","bool":true}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"At what level does the pulmonary trunk bifurcate into pulmonary arteries?","answers":[{"option":"3rd costal cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"1st intercostal space","bool":false},{"option":"2nd costal cartilage","bool":true},{"option":"3rd intercostal space","bool":false},{"option":"1st costal cartilage","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following is best described as the pressure between the lung pleura and the chest pleura?","answers":[{"option":"Intrapulmonary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Transpulmonary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural pressure","bool":true},{"option":"Intrathoracic pressure","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"At what vertebral level does the thoracic duct enter into the posterior mediastinum?","answers":[{"option":"T12","bool":true},{"option":"L2","bool":false},{"option":"L1","bool":false},{"option":"T8","bool":false},{"option":"T10","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following best describes the chest placement during a posteroanterior (PA) view of a chest x-ray?","answers":[{"option":"Supinated against detector","bool":false},{"option":"Back towards detector","bool":false},{"option":"Face towards detector","bool":true},{"option":"Midclavicular line towards detector","bool":false},{"option":"Midaxillary line towards detector","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following structures is not in the vicinity of the transverse plane present at the sternal angle and T4/T5 vertebrae?","answers":[{"option":"Left common carotid","bool":false},{"option":"Azygous vein drains into SVC","bool":false},{"option":"Right brachiocephalic trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Bifurcation of trachea","bool":false},{"option":"Right common carotid artery","bool":true}]},{"id":65,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following subset of cells is involved in the pathogenesis of asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Natural killer cells","bool":false},{"option":"T-helper 2 (Th2) cells","bool":true},{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false},{"option":"T-helper 1 (Th1) cells","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Tobacco is known to have more than 3900 compounds in it. Which of the following is likely to cause the most damage to the body?","answers":[{"option":"Ammonia","bool":false},{"option":"Nicotine","bool":true},{"option":"Butane","bool":false},{"option":"Arsenic","bool":false},{"option":"Lead","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following is best defined as a condition in which ventilation decreases and the partial pressure of carbon dioxide increases?","answers":[{"option":"Compensatory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A student has exam anxiety and starts hyperventilating. Which of the following will be the most likely outcome in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":true},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Compensatory alkalosis","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"What is the term for the 8th to the 16th week of the respiratory system development stage?","answers":[{"option":"Canalicular stage","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar stage","bool":false},{"option":"Embryonic stage","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudoglandular stage","bool":true},{"option":"Terminal sac stage","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following is responsible for transporting the greatest amount of oxygen in the blood?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma","bool":false},{"option":"Bicarbonate ions","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobin","bool":true},{"option":"Albumin","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most likely value for barometric pressure at sea level?","answers":[{"option":"76 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"800 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"100 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"120 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"760 mm of Hg","bool":true}]},{"id":72,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"At which vertebral level is the thoracic duct most likely to exit the posterior mediastinum?","answers":[{"option":"T10","bool":false},{"option":"T5","bool":true},{"option":"T2","bool":false},{"option":"T8","bool":false},{"option":"T12","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"The mediastinal surface of the left lung has a groove for which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Ascending aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Arch of azygous vein","bool":false},{"option":"Arch of aorta","bool":true},{"option":"Superior vena cava","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which type of epithelium lines the olfactory epithelium?","answers":[{"option":"Simple columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified columnar with glandular cells","bool":true},{"option":"Simple cuboidal","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified columnar without glandular cells","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following is inhibited by non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs)?","answers":[{"option":"Cyclooxygenase pathway","bool":true},{"option":"Prostaglandins","bool":false},{"option":"Thromboxane A2","bool":false},{"option":"Lipooxygenase pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotrienes","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following is a major cause of cancer, contributing to almost 22% of cancer-related deaths worldwide?","answers":[{"option":"Environmental pollutants","bool":false},{"option":"Sun exposure","bool":false},{"option":"Tobacco","bool":true},{"option":"Radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocarbons","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A 17-year-old man travels to a mountainous area and stays there for years. His body undergoes the process of acclimatization. Which of the following changes is likely to occur in his body?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased use of oxygen by tissues despite low partial pressure of oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased ventilation","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased red blood cell count","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased breathing rate","bool":false},{"option":"Increased peripheral vascularization","bool":true}]},{"id":78,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following best describes asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Contagious disease","bool":false},{"option":"Communicable disease","bool":false},{"option":"Atopic disease","bool":true},{"option":"Malignant disease","bool":false},{"option":"Autoimmune diease","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"The visceral pleura is innervated by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Only intercostal nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Collateral intercostal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomic nervous system (vasomotor)","bool":true},{"option":"Phrenic nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following cells mediate allergic response in atopic asthma?","answers":[{"option":"T helper 1 (Th1) cells","bool":false},{"option":"T helper 2 (Th2) cells","bool":true},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"The enzyme phospholipase A2 is involved in which of the following reactions?","answers":[{"option":"Synthesis of triacylglycerol (TAG)","bool":false},{"option":"Breakdown of sphingolipid","bool":false},{"option":"Breakdown of sphingomyelin","bool":false},{"option":"Breakdown of triacylglycerol (TAG)","bool":false},{"option":"Breakdown of phosphoglycerides","bool":true}]},{"id":82,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A physician examines an X-ray of the anterior thoracic wall. Which of the following structures constitute this wall?","answers":[{"option":"Intervertebral discs","bool":false},{"option":"Manubrium, body of sternum and xiphoid process","bool":true},{"option":"Intercoastal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic vertebrae","bool":false},{"option":"Ribs","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following nerves innervates the diaphragm?","answers":[{"option":"Phrenic","bool":true},{"option":"Iliohypogastric","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus","bool":false},{"option":"Intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"Subcoastal","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A resident in the emergency room, while performing pleural effusion drainage, consciously inserts the needle in the 3rd intercostal space just above the inferior rib. This avoids damage to which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral pleura","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal pleura","bool":false},{"option":"Intercostal nerve and vessels","bool":true},{"option":"Pericardium","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"What is the value for barometric pressure at sea level?","answers":[{"option":"1 mm of Hg","bool":false},{"option":"1 atm","bool":true},{"option":"70 atm","bool":false},{"option":"76 atm","bool":false},{"option":"760 atm","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A benign tumor originating from glandular epithelium is termed as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Papilloma","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Krukenberg tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Adenoma","bool":true},{"option":"Carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following actions of the respiratory system leads to the development of respiratory alkalosis?","answers":[{"option":"Remove excess amount of oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"Retain excess amount of hydrogen ions","bool":false},{"option":"Remove excess amount of carbon dioxide","bool":true},{"option":"Retain excess amount of oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"Retain excess amount of carbon dioxide","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A patient is admitted to the hospital with severe pleuritis. The amount of proteins in the pleural fluid is likely to be more than which of the following in this case?","answers":[{"option":"3 g/L","bool":false},{"option":"5 g/L","bool":false},{"option":"10 g/L","bool":false},{"option":"20 g/L","bool":false},{"option":"30 g/L","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"The contraction of which of the following muscles is not involved in inspiration?","answers":[{"option":"Scalenus anterior","bool":false},{"option":"External intercostal","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":false},{"option":"Internal intercostal","bool":true},{"option":"Serratus anterior","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A 65-year-old female is admitted to the ICU. She develops chest pain 3 days later. A  chest X-ray is performed and reveals diffuse lung infiltrates. What is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Interstitial disease of lung","bool":false},{"option":"Community acquired pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Nosocomial pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Lung abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Granulomatous disease of lung","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A student is studying the contents of the superior mediastinum. Which of the following structures is not present in the mentioned region?","answers":[{"option":"Left common carotid","bool":false},{"option":"Arch of azygous vein","bool":false},{"option":"Right common carotid","bool":true},{"option":"Arch of aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Brachiocephalic veins","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A 60-year-old female presents with complaints of difficulty in breathing particularly in the morning and during changes in position. She is coughing up a copious amount of mucus. Which of the following conditions is the most likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"A hospitalized patient suffers from respiratory distress and difficulty breathing. Chest x-ray reveals a white lung. Which of the following is the likely diagnosis in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS)","bool":true},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following cells is present in the intra-alveolar septa besides pneumocytes?","answers":[{"option":"Dust cells","bool":true},{"option":"Sustentacular cells","bool":false},{"option":"Receptor cells","bool":false},{"option":"Basal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Columnar cells","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"1st-year/respiratory/2021","question":"Which of the following enzymes causes the breakdown of phosphoglyceride?","answers":[{"option":"Lipofructokinase","bool":false},{"option":"Sphingomyelinase","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Phospholipase","bool":true},{"option":"Transferase","bool":false}]}]
export default arr